Vinícius Soares da Silva Melo

E-mail: vinicius.coding@gmail.com | Phone: +55 (85) 988194897 | Age: 19 years old.

Endereço: Rua Joaquim Jerônimo, 559, BL 02, AP 01. Mondubim, Fortaleza-CE. **Linkedin**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vin%C3%ADcius-soares-584075255/

Github: https://github.com/Vini-Coding

Profile

I am a Jr. Flutter Developer and UI Designer. Started programming at 15 during my technical High School and Flutter development 1 year and 5 months ago. I always appreciate a clean code, and can adapt quickly to your code architecture. My goal is always help to develop the best solution possible.

Languages

- Portuguese (Native, C2).
- English (Advanced, C1).

Technical High School in Computer Networks

German (Basic, A1).

Education

State School of Professional Education Juarez Tavora	Fortaleza, Ceará. Brazil
Courses	
Coding: Programming Preparatory Course Federal University of Ceará.	02/2019 – 12/2019 Fortaleza, Ceará. Brazil
Git and Github Course CursoemVideo.	06/2020 – 07/2020 Remote, Brazil
$\begin{tabular}{ll} And roid/iOS/Web Apps creation with Flutter - 5 Courses in 1 \\ \it Startto. dev \end{tabular}$	09/2022 – present Remote, Brazil

01/2019 - 01/2022

Technical Skills

- State Management with Change and ValueNotifier.
- Dependency Injection with Provider and Injector packages.
- Navigation with Named Routes and Arguments.
- Exceptions Handling with abstraction.
- BloC Pattern.
- MVC and MPVC patterns.
- Local data persistence with SharedPreferences, Hive and SQLite.
- API Rest.
- Flutter Themes implementation with Material3.
- Internationalization with flutter_localizations package.
- User Interface Design.
- Clean Code.

Projects

BMI Check: Calculate your BMI and discover if you are in your ideal body mass index and what is your body weight in a custom text with Health recommendations, and share with in social media. You can also change the height and weight metrics, switch between dark and

light theme and choose your language from about 10 options available.

Repository Link: https://github.com/Vini-Coding/BMI-Check

Professional Experience

Freelance of Flutter Front-End Development

Company: Polygonus (MG, Brazil). Period: 01/15/2023 – 05/01/2023.

Trainee in Flutter Mobile Development

Company: G4Flex Business & Services (CE, Brazil).

Period: 01/01/2022 - 06/01/2022.

Trainee in Salesforce Administration

Company: G4Flex Business & Services (CE, Brazil).

Period: 10/25/2021 - 01/30/2021.

Honors and Awards

Third Place Winner in IV Hackaton of Feira do Conhecimento, developed by *Secretary of Science, Technology and College Education of the State of Ceará* about developing solutions to problems in different areas of Brazil. [11/09/2022].

News Link: https://www.sct.ce.gov.br/2022/11/13/fdc-conheca-os-vencedores-do-4o-hackathon-do-conhecimento/